zeal.com 2006-03-14

# Privacy Policy

About Zeal  
 Press Room  
Terms of Use  
**Privacy Policy** |  | **Privacy Policy** | Last Updated: 07/19/01  
---|---  
Zeal is committed to safeguarding your privacy while using our service. Zeal's parent company, LookSmart, Ltd., shares this respect for your privacy. Please read the following policy to understand how your personal information will be treated as you make full use of our offerings. While Zeal's commitment to your privacy will not waiver, we may be required to change the details of our privacy policy from time to time, so please check back periodically.  
---  
   
If you have any questions about this privacy statement, the practices of this site or your dealings with this Web site, email [privacy@looksmart.net](mailto:privacy@looksmart.net?subject=Zeal%20Privacy%20Policy).  
   
This policy will let you know:  
  
  * What if Zeal modifies the Privacy Policy?
  * What personally identifiable information does Zeal collect from me?
  * What are cookies and how does Zeal use them?
  * Who is collecting my information?
  * How does Zeal use my information?
  * With whom does Zeal share my information?
  * What are my choices regarding collection, use, and distribution of my information?
  * What is Zeal's policy on allowing me to update, correct, or delete my personally identifiable information?
  * What security precautions are in place to protect the loss, misuse, or alteration of my information?
  * What about children's privacy?
  * What else should I know about my privacy?
  * What if Zeal modifies the Privacy Policy?
  * Additional Questions

**What if Zeal modifies the Privacy Policy?**  
---  
Zeal may need to modify the privacy policy due to updates and changes in the service. Modifications will continue to respect and safeguard your privacy while adjusting the policy to account for evolving features and services that Zeal provides. Please review the privacy policy from time to time to ensure you have read the most recent version.  
   
**What personally identifiable information does Zeal collect from me?**  
Zeal collects information in several ways from different parts of our website. Some personal information is gathered when you register. During registration, Zeal requires a unique public member identity (not your real name), private password, and a valid email address. No other personal information is required for users to use the Zeal service. Once you register, you are no longer anonymous to Zeal. Your member name is made public to the Zeal Community. All other required information is not shared publicly unless the you choose to reveal it.  
   
Beyond registration, you may provide voluntary personal information at other times, including (but not limited to) when you create a Member Profile, provide opinions or ratings, enter a sweepstakes, contest, or promotion sponsored by Zeal and/or our partners, and when you report a problem with one of our features or services. If you contact Zeal we may keep a record of that correspondence. Zeal also occasionally asks users to complete surveys that we use for research purposes. Wherever Zeal collects personal information, we make an effort to include a link to this Privacy Policy on that page. Zeal may at times also collect IP addresses and login records for system administration and to report aggregate information to our advertisers. We may also collect information through the use of "pixel tags" included in email messages we may send to you. Pixel tags are tiny graphic files, not visible to the human eye, that are included in HTML-encoded email messages. When such a message is opened in an HTML-capable email program, the recipient's computer will access our server to retrieve the pixel tag file, allowing us to record and store, along with the recipient's email address, the date and time the recipient viewed the email message, that the recipient's email program is capable of receiving HTML-encoded email, and other standard logging information. The pixel tag also may see or read cookies.  
   
**What are cookies and how does Zeal use them?**  
As part of offering and providing customizable and personalized services, Zeal uses cookies to store and sometimes track information about you. A cookie is a small amount of data that is sent to your browser from a web server and stored on your computer's hard drive. All web pages on Zeal where you are prompted to login or that are customizable may require that you accept cookies. (See "What are my choices regarding collection, use and distribution of my information?" for more information on cookies.)  
   
Generally, we use cookies to:  
  
  1. Remind us of who you are and to access your account information (stored on our computers) in order to deliver to you a better and more personalized service. This cookie is set when you register or "log in" and is modified when you "log out" of our services.
  2. Estimate our audience size. Each browser accessing Zeal is given a unique cookie which is then used to determine the extent of repeat usage, usage by a registered user versus by an unregistered user, and to help target advertisements based on user interests and behavior.
  3. Assist Zeal partners or affiliates to track visits to and business with their companies, and potentially to process the items in your shopping basket. This information collected by cookies is sometimes called "clickstream" or "click trail" and may also describe which pages you have seen in each merchant's store.
  4. Track your progress and number of entries in some of our promotions, sweepstakes, and contests.
  5. Measure certain traffic patterns, which areas of the Zeal sites you have visited, and your visiting patterns in the aggregate. We use this research to understand how our users' habits are similar to or different from one another so that we can make each new experience on Zeal a better one. We may use this information to better personalize the content, banners, and promotions that you and other users will see on our sites.

Advertising networks that serve ads onto Zeal may also use their own cookies. The content of such cookies and the use of the information they contain is controlled by the third party advertising network placing them, not by Zeal. If you would like a list of the advertising networks with whom Zeal does business, send an email to [privacy@looksmart.net](mailto:privacy@looksmart.net?subject=Zeal%20Privacy%20Policy).  
   
**Who is collecting my information?**  
When you are on a Zeal site and are asked for personal information, you are sharing that information with Zeal alone, unless it is specifically stated otherwise. For example, some Zeal services may be offered in conjunction with a partner company. In order to provide this co-branded service to you, it may be necessary for us to share your personal information with our partner company. If data is being collected and/or maintained by any company other than Zeal, you will be notified prior to the time of the data collection or transfer. If you do not want your data to be shared, you can choose not to allow the transfer by not using that particular service.  
   
Promotions that run on Zeal may be sponsored by companies other than Zeal or may be cosponsored by Zeal and another company. Some or all data collected during a promotion may be shared with the sponsor. If data will be shared, you will be notified prior to the time of data collection or transfer. You can decide not to participate in the promotion if you don't want your data to be shared.  
   
Please be aware that Zeal advertisers or web sites that have links on our site may collect personally identifiable information about you once you have clicked through to their sites. This privacy statement does not cover the information practices of those web sites linked to or from Zeal.  
   
**How does Zeal use my information?**  
Zeal's primary goal in collecting personal information is to provide you, the user, with a customized experience on our service. This includes, or may include in the future, personalization services, interactive communications, online shopping, and many other types of services, most of which are completely free to you. In order to provide services free of charge, we display advertisements. By knowing a little about you, Zeal is able to deliver more relevant advertisements and content, and hence better service, to you.  
   
**With whom does Zeal share my information?**  
As a general rule, Zeal will not disclose any of your personally identifiable information except when we have your permission or under special circumstances, such as when we believe in good faith that the law requires it or under the circumstances described below. Certain Zeal services may be subject to specific Terms of Use; please see the Terms of Use for each of our services, if they exist, for more detailed information about how your personal information may be shared. The following describes some of the ways that your information may be disclosed.  
   
Business Partners & Sponsors: Zeal may disclose your personal information to business partners or sponsors, but this is specifically described to you prior to data collection or prior to transferring the data. Details of shared use can be found in specific Terms of Use or Official Rules for specific sweepstakes and promotions. If personally identifiable data about you will be shared in connection with a particular activity on the site, we will tell you before we collect or transfer the data, and give you the opportunity not to proceed with that activity.  
   
Many promotions offer opportunities to request additional information from sponsors. By requesting more information, you give Zeal permission to transfer your personal information to the sponsor so they can fulfill your request. In many instances, only your email address will be shared. If more information will be shared with the sponsor, you will be notified prior to the transfer, and given an opportunity to withdraw your request.  
   
From time to time, you may be offered the opportunity to receive materials or special offers from third parties. If you opt-in to receive information from these third parties, Zeal will share your name and email address with those parties.  
   
Data in the Aggregate: Zeal discloses aggregated user statistics (for example, 45% of our users are male) in order to describe our services to prospective partners, advertisers, and other third parties, and for other lawful purposes.  
   
Other: Zeal may also disclose account information in special cases when we have reason to believe that disclosing this information is necessary to identify, contact, or bring legal action against someone who may be violating Zeal's Terms of Use or may be causing injury to or interference with (either intentionally or unintentionally) Zeal's rights or property, other Zeal users, or anyone else that could be harmed by such activities. Zeal may disclose or access account information when we believe in good faith that the law requires it and for administrative and other purposes that we deem necessary to maintain, service, and improve our products and services.  
   
**What are my choices regarding collection, use, and distribution of my information?**  
Zeal may, from time to time, send you email regarding our products and services. In most cases, you will be given the opportunity to choose not to receive these messages. In some instances, emails are a necessary component of Zeal's service. In addition, if you indicated upon registration that you are interested in receiving offers or information from Zeal and our partners, we may occasionally send you email about products and services that we feel may be of interest to you. Only Zeal (or agents working on behalf of Zeal and under confidentiality agreements) will send you these mailings and only if you indicated that you do not object to these offers. If you do not want to receive such mailings, simply tell us when you register or change your preference in your Member Profile. You will need your Zeal member name and password in order to access your Member Profile.  
   
On some types of Zeal promotions, we may ask for your email address in order to update you on your score, entries, and status in prize drawings. When you participate in these types of promotions, you may automatically receive promotion-related email. Occasionally these promotion-related email messages may include targeted advertisements.  
   
You also have choices with respect to cookies. By modifying your browser preferences, you have the choice to accept all cookies, to be notified when a cookie is set, or to reject all cookies. If you choose to reject all cookies you will be unable to use those Zeal services that require cookies in order to participate. You can still experience many features on the Zeal site even if you do not accept cookies.  
   
We will notify you at the time of data collection or transfer if your data will be shared with a third party and you will always have the option of not permitting the transfer. If you do not wish to allow your data to be shared, you can choose not to use a particular service or not to participate in certain promotions or contests.  
   
**What is Zeal's policy on allowing me to update, correct, or delete my personally identifiable information?**  
You may edit your Member Profile at any time by selecting Profile within the Zeal service and then using your member name and password.  
   
Your Zeal account can be deactivated and personally identifiable information deleted, but doing so will result in not being able to access any members-only area of the Zeal service. Please contact [zeal_community@looksmart.net](mailto:zeal_community@looksmart.net) if you wish to deactivate your account, clearly indicating the nature of your request.  
   
**What security precautions are in place to protect the loss, misuse, or alteration of my information?**  
Your Zeal Account Information and Member Profile are password-protected so that you and only you have access to entering and editing personal information, or in the case of your Member Profile, choosing to display publicly this personal information. You may edit your Account Information or Member Profile using your member name and password.  
   
Your member name is the one part of your member profile that always remains public. Because Zeal is an interactive and community driven directory, it is important for other users to know who has submitted content, ratings, and reviews.  
   
We recommend that you do not divulge your password to anyone. Zeal will never ask you for your password in an unsolicited phone call or in an unsolicited email. Please remember to log out of your Zeal account and close your browser window when you have finished your work. This helps ensure that others cannot access your personal information and correspondence if you share a computer with someone else or are using a computer in a public place like a library or Internet cafe.  
   
As a global service Zeal has users all over the world. When you give Zeal personal information, that information may be sent electronically to servers outside of the country where you originally entered the information, such as to the United States or other countries. In addition, that information may be used, stored and processed outside of the country where you entered that information. Unfortunately, no data transmission over the Internet can be guaranteed to be secure. As a result, while we strive to protect your personal information, Zeal cannot ensure or warrant the security of any information you transmit to us or from our online products or services, and you do so at your own risk. Once we receive your transmission, we make our best effort to ensure its security on our systems.  
   
**What about children's privacy?**  
Zeal does not accept members who are under the age of 13. In accordance with the [Children's Online Privacy Protection Act](http://www.ftc.gov/ogc/coppa1.htm) (COPPA), Zeal will not knowingly collect personal information from a child under the age of 13.  
   
**What else should I know about my privacy?**  
Please keep in mind that whenever you voluntarily disclose personal information online - for example on message boards, through email, or in chat areas - that information can be collected and used by others. Thus, if you post personal information online that is accessible to the public, you may receive unsolicited and unwanted communications from other parties in return.  
   
Ultimately, you are solely responsible for maintaining the secrecy of your passwords and/or any account information. Please be careful and responsible whenever you're online.  
   
**What if Zeal modifies the Privacy Policy?**  
Zeal may need to modify the privacy policy due to updates and changes in the service. Modifications will continue to respect and safeguard your privacy while adjusting the policy to account for evolving features and services that Zeal provides. Please review the privacy policy from time to time to ensure you have read the most recent version.  
   
**Additional Questions**  
Questions regarding this statement should be directed to  
Privacy Policy  
Zeal Privacy Policy  
c/o LookSmart, Ltd.  
625 Second Street  
San Francisco, CA 94107  
or  
[privacy@looksmart.net](mailto:privacy@looksmart.net?subject=Zeal%20Privacy%20Policy).   
   
**Back to Top**
